Will O'Neill

Writer, Narrative Designer and Game Developer

706-410 Queens Quay W.
Toronto, ON M5V 3T1
(647) 206-7504
will.oneill@outlook.com
https://willoneill.carrd.co/

EXPERIENCE

WZO Games Inc., Toronto — *Job Title*

2013 - PRESENT

Creator of the critically acclaimed narrative-focused games Actual Sunlight, Little Red Lie and F2P mobile game Guildmaster Story.

Pillow Castle Games, Seattle — Writer

2019 - PRESENT

Writing and narrative development on SUPERLIMINAL.

Power Struggle Games, Lyon — *Writer & Narrative Designer*

2019 - PRESENT

Writing and narrative development on The Invisible Hand.

EDUCATION

University of Toronto, Toronto — Bachelor of Arts

2000 - 2004

English and Philosophy

Centennial College, Toronto — *Postgraduate Certificate*

2004 - 2005

Public Relations & Corporate Communications

TRAINING

Unreal Engine — *Udemy*

Completed Ben Tristem course on Blueprint development and Rick Davidson course on cinematic development

Unity — Certified Developer

Passed exam on first attempt, prepped via Ben Tristem Udemy course.

HIGHLIGHTS

11,000+ Reviews on Steam

Eight games shipped on all current platforms - Steam, PS4, PS Vita, Xbox, iOS and Android - including three self-published on PC and console

8+ years experience in games writing, with 10+ in corporate communications and copywriting

SKILLS

Engines: Unity, RPG Maker, Adventure Game Studio (AGS), Ren'py

Narrative Tools: Articy Draft, Arcweave, Adventure Creator, Fungus

Voiceover Direction: Remote and in-studio, extensive across game and corporate clients

Production: Affinity Photo / Designer, Adobe Photoshop / Illustrator, Logic Pro, Audacity, Shotcut, Final Cut Pro

Publishing: Managed Steam and console submissions – TRC process, ratings (IARC, ESRB, PEGI), store submissions, etc.